# Frederick Carnes

I was born in Boston, MA in 1980. I grew up in a small town called Bridgewater, MA and lived there until 2001 when I joined the U.S. Army as a Paratrooper in the 82nd Airborne Division. In 2006, after completing 3 combat tours, and almost 5 years of service, I received an honorable discharge at the rank of Sergeant, and moved to Coral Springs, FL.

I started working for a security company and worked my way up from a Security Officer to the Operations Director in two short years. I held the ranks of "Officer", "Post Captain", "Major", "Field Training Officer", and "Chief Field Training Officer" before obtaining the Director position. I worked there from 2006 until 2010 when my wife and I moved to where her family was located in Garnet Valley, Pennsylvania.

Two years after that I started working at the University of Pennsylvania as a Gardener. I have worked at UPenn now for 7 years and that is where I learned of a course offered called "UPenn Coding Bootcamp ". I am now enrolled in the Coding Bootcamp to explore my lifelong passion with computers by learning to code software.

It is my goal to obtain a career that I will love instead of just working for the money. This is a career path that I am very excited to explore.

#### Education

University of Pennsylvania Certificate

Philadelphia Pennsylvania Graduatina October 2019

Coding BootCamp - Full Stack Developer Program

## Professional Skills

HTMI

**CSS** 

Javascript

jQuery

React.js

node.js

Bootstrap

Flexbox

MongoDB

## Languages

English

HTML

**CSS** Javascript Conversational

#### Employment History

#### UNIVERSITY OF **PENNSYLVANIA**

July 2012 - Present

Union Shop Steward

• Earned the trust and respect of my co-worker's to be voted the Union Shop Steward in less than one year. Negotiate, proofed, and approved contracts for the Collective Bargaining Unit with the University. Responsible for scheduling overtime for 30 employees. File and conference for grievances due to contract violations. • Resolve compensation, accrued time issues, and coworker friction for the shop. Maintain an assigned area of the campus on a daily basis. • Ensure the planting and trimming of plants, trees, and pulling of weeds is completed as needed.. Mulching, fertilizing, and policing of the area. Snow Removal.

#### Fortress Protective Services, Inc. Operations Director

May 2006 - June 2010

· Consulted with clients daily to ensure that they were receiving the best possible service. Supervised 2 area managers, 17 site managers and approximately 160 employees. Responsible for all training, supervision, and human resource management functions of approximately 160 employees. Conducted performance reviews on all employees on a yearly basis covering work quality, attendance and uniform appearance, in order to meet the standards for promotions and raises. • Reduced overtime by 25% in first 3 months of being promoted to Operations Director. Responsible for ensuring all accounts were staffed with qualified people. Over a period of 6 to efficiently cover absences, resulting in reducing overtime from 3.9% to 2%, a \$2000 per week savings. Obtained an

months, cross trained employees working in different locations employee turnover rate of less than 33% in an industry with an average turnover rate of 125%. Performed all interviews of potential employees, and the discipline of current employees. Worked with all of the outside vendors to provide main office, and 17 remote locations, with anything needed. From office supplies to new security cameras, to HVAC repairs and new lights. • Implemented the Company Drug Free workplace policy. Found non-evasive, cost effective, drug tests that could be administered in our office, with results in 15 minutes. Resulted in an average savings of \$103 per test over using traditional drug testing United States Army 82nd Airborne Division

## Sergeant / Infantry Team

October 2001 - May 2006

Leader / Operations Non Commissioned Officer In

• Personally selected to be a part of the Presidential security team that was taken from Afghanistan to Pakistan for the March 4th US Presidential visit in 2006 protecting President George W. Bush. • Responsible for over \$10M worth of equipment. • Performed over fifty raids on enemy and suspected enemy compounds over the span of 3 combat tours. Duties entailed being a rifleman in Afghanistan to being a Team Leader in both Afghanistan and Iraq. Non-commissioned Officer in charge of the Tactical Operations Center. Authorized the arrival and departure of every patrol that was involved with the Forward Observation Base my company occupied, as well as the recording of any intelligence and patrol positions that the patrols would report. Maintained constant communication with supply channels to ensure that the company had the materials that were needed on a day to day basis. Responsible for training, accountability, health, moral, welfare, and providing guidance for the professional development of a five member team. • Investigated pay discrepancies for a 120 person company resolving all issues under strict time lines and restrictions. • Performed all personnel management functions for US government contractors including pay, vacations, and planned absences. Devised and implemented a training plan to insure smooth transition of daily running and organization of the company's Operations office. • Company Physical Security Non Commissioned Officer. Responsible for composing daily intelligence reports and presenting them to the Commander.

